<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Cornell CoLab&#x27;s Guides</title>
    <link href="https://cornellcolab.github.io/guides/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://cornellcolab.github.io/guides" />
    <updated>2022-10-16T18:38:31-04:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>The Digital CoLab at Cornell University Library</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://cornellcolab.github.io/guides</id>

    <entry>
        <title>Guides from the Digital CoLab</title>
        <author>
            <name>The Digital CoLab at Cornell University Library</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://cornellcolab.github.io/guides/guide/"/>
        <id>https://cornellcolab.github.io/guides/guide/</id>

        <updated>2022-10-16T18:38:31-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    The Digital CoLab supports new and experimental approaches to research and teaching that are most often associated with the humanities and qualitative social sciences. We offer&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>The Digital CoLab supports new and experimental approaches to research and teaching that are most often associated with the humanities and qualitative social sciences.</p>
<p>We offer <a href="https://digitalscholarship.library.cornell.edu/contact">one-on-one consultations</a>, <a href="https://digitalscholarship.library.cornell.edu/education">workshops</a>, and <a href="https://digitalscholarship.library.cornell.edu/contact">classroom instruction</a> on projects including:</p>
<ul>
<li>Digital exhibits or digital publications</li>
<li>Maps</li>
<li>Privacy</li>
<li>Computational text analysis (Words are data too!)</li>
<li>Finding or preparing</li>
<li>Network analysis</li>
<li>Database design and maintenance</li>
<li>Finding or preparing data with Optical Character Recognition (OCR), APIs, webscraping or other methods.</li>
<li>Troubleshooting or remixing Python or R code for any of the above tasks. </li>
</ul>
<p><a href="https://digitalscholarship.library.cornell.edu/about">Learn more about our work</a>.</p>
<p><a href="http://digitalscholarship.library.cornell.edu/contact">Contact us</a> to sign up for our weekly newsletter or ask questions.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Digital Harassment Self-Defense</title>
        <author>
            <name>The Digital CoLab at Cornell University Library</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://cornellcolab.github.io/guides/harassment/"/>
        <id>https://cornellcolab.github.io/guides/harassment/</id>

        <updated>2022-10-16T18:22:04-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Threat Models Any good security plan starts with a threat model (aka a risk assessment), however vague at first. As you continue to plan and&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <h2>Threat Models</h2>
<p> Any good security plan starts with a threat model (aka a risk assessment), however vague at first. As you continue to plan and take actions, the threat model can become a touchstone that helps you decide which actions are worthwhile for you. Start with this introduction from the Electronic Freedom Foundation. </p>
<p><a data-cke-saved-href="https://www.eff.org/files/2020/01/06/threatmodeling-onepager.pdf" href="https://www.eff.org/files/2020/01/06/threatmodeling-onepager.pdf">Risk Assessment one-pager</a>, Electronic Frontier Foundation (2019).</p>
<p class="msg msg--info">For background reading to help inform your threat model, see the section Understanding Harassment below. </p>
<h2>Secure Your Accounts</h2>
<p>Ideally, <em>each</em> of your accounts will have a unique, hard-to-guess password. Creation and storage of most of these passwords are best left to a password manager.</p>
<p>But for your most important accounts, you may want to create your own memorable, strong passwords, and keep them out of your password manager. You may also want to enable two-factor authentication for these most important accounts. </p>
<p>Don't forget to create a strong, memorable password for your password manager itself!</p>
<h3>Create Strong Passwords</h3>
<p><a href="https://ssd.eff.org/en/module/creating-strong-passwords">How to Create Strong Passwords</a>, Electronic Freedom Foundation (2021)</p>
<h3>Choose and Maintain a Password Manager</h3>
<p><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/wirecutter/blog/why-you-need-a-password-manager-yes-you/">Why You Need a Password Manager. Yes, You.</a>, A. Cunningham (2021). <em>Wirecutter: The New York Times</em></p>
<p><a href="https://haveibeenpwned.com/">Have I Been Pwned?</a> A safe, free tool that allows you to see if your email address(es) has been a username in any known credential hacks.</p>
<p>Choose a password manager, and install it on all your devices:</p>
<h5>Bitwarden</h5>
<aside class="post__note">
<ul>
<li><a href="https://bitwarden.com/">Bitwarden Sign Up</a></li>
<li><a href="https://bitwarden.com/help/">Official Help Docs</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qzuut0-noHk">An unofficial video introduction</a></li>
</ul>
</aside>
<p><em><strong>Pros</strong></em><em> </em>Open source. Well-designed and easy to use. Free for individuals.</p>
<p><em><strong>Cons</strong></em><em>: Slightly</em> less user-friendly than 1Password</p>
<p><em><strong>Cost </strong></em>Free for up to 2 individuals. $40/year for families.</p>
<h5>1Password</h5>
<aside class="post__note">
<ul>
<li><a href="https://1password.com/">1Password Sign Up</a></li>
<li><a href="https://support.1password.com/">Official Help Docs</a></li>
</ul>
</aside>
<p><em><strong>Pros:</strong></em><em> </em>The absolute simplest to use, in our opinion.</p>
<p><em><strong>Cons</strong></em><em>: </em>No free tier</p>
<p><em><strong>Cost: </strong></em>$36/yr for individuals, $60/yr for families</p>
<h5>LastPass</h5>
<aside class="post__note">
<ul>
<li><a href="https://it.cornell.edu/password-mgmt">LastPass Sign Up through Cornell</a></li>
<li><a href="https://support.logmeininc.com/lastpass">Official Help Docs</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=j8Wj4oBy3os">An unofficial instructional video</a></li>
</ul>
</aside>
<p><em><strong>Pros:</strong></em><em> </em>Supported by Cornell while you're affiliated.</p>
<p><em><strong>Cons:</strong></em><em> </em>It's the only third-party password manager known to have experienced a security breach (but no passwords were accessed). Also, recent purchase by venture capital firm raises questions.</p>
<p><em><strong>Cost</strong></em>: Free Personal plan or Family plan for Cornell affiliates.<br>After Cornell affiliation ends: Free for one individual and <em>one device, </em>$36/yr for full-featured individual plan, $48/yr for families.</p>
<h3>Enable Multi-Factor Authentication</h3>
<p>For your most important or most sensitive accounts, consider enabling two-factor authentication (2FA) with an authenticator app, a hardware token -- or both, which lets each act as a backup for the other.</p>
<p class="msg msg--warning">The easiest and often default 2FA method is plain text SMS. But this is also the least secure method, as a determined adversary can spoof your phone number if they know it, and intercept plain SMS texts. That's why we recommend an authenticator app or hardware token. </p>
<h5><strong>Authenticator Apps</strong></h5>
<p>Authenticator apps are free for individual end users (like you) because their profit comes from the tech companies that pay for them to be compatible with their sites, and by enterprise customers (like Cornell).</p>
<p>Authenticator apps explained: <a href="https://www.vox.com/recode/22419794/authenticator-apps-and-you-authy-google-authenticator">There's a Better Way to Protect Yourself from Hackers and Identity Thieves</a>, S. Morrison (2021). <em>Vox recode.</em></p>
<p>You probably already use one authenticator app -- Duo Mobile -- to access your Cornell account. <a href="https://guide.duo.com/third-party-accounts">Follow these instructions to add additional third-party accounts to Duo Mobile</a>.</p>
<p><a href="https://authy.com">Authy</a> is another free and trustworthy authenticator app.</p>
<h5><strong>Authentication with a Hardware Token</strong></h5>
<p>A hardware token is the most secure form of 2FA. It's a small physical item that looks slightly like a thumb drive. Keep it with you -- on your keychain, for example -- and plug it into your device's USB or Lightning drive with you need authentication. It's particularly useful if you need 2FA access when you don't have reliable cellular service, or if you use burner phones.</p>
<p>Hardware tokens explained: <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/how-to-use-a-yubikey/">Simplify and Secure Your Online Accounts with a Yubikey</a>, J Colt (2018). <em>WIRED.</em></p>
<p>The <a href="https://www.yubico.com/">Yubikey</a> is the most popular brand of authenticator hardware token</p>
<h2>Data Brokers</h2>
<h3>Remove Your Details from Data Broker Storehouses</h3>
<p>DIY: <a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1nJS9LJV7QCxl2d6DcTuao_lPfeT2gYgfWpvRzpSUEwU/edit?pli=1">Reanna's Big List of data brokers and their opt-out links</a></p>
<p>If you decide to hire a service: <a href="https://joindeleteme.com/">DeleteMe</a></p>
<h3>Plug Some Leaky Data Holes</h3>
<p>Install tracking blocker extensions on your web browsers, like <a href="https://privacybadger.org/">Privacy Badger</a> or <a href="https://ublockorigin.com/">uBlock Origin</a>.</p>
<p>Delete apps from your phone that you don't need.</p>
<p>Follow t<a href="https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2019/12/19/opinion/location-tracking-privacy-tips.html">hese steps for limiting location tracking on your phone</a>. (<em>NYTimes</em>, Dec. 2019)</p>
<h3>Background Reading on Data Brokers</h3>
<h5><strong><em>Public-Facing Data Brokers</em></strong></h5>
<p><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2019/08/15/technology/personaltech/i-shared-my-phone-number-i-learned-i-shouldnt-have.html">I Shared My Phone Number. I Learned I Shouldn't Have.</a> (B. Chen, <em>NYTimes. </em>Aug. 15, 2019.)</p>
<h5><strong><em>On the Failures of "Anonymized" Data</em></strong></h5>
<p><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2019/12/21/opinion/pasadena-smartphone-spying.html">Where Even the Children Are Being Tracked</a> (C. Warzel &amp; S. Thompson, <em>NYTimes. </em>Dec. 21, 2019)</p>
<h5><strong><em>Phone Apps</em></strong></h5>
<p><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2019/09/24/opinion/facebook-google-apps-data.html">The Loophole That Turns Your Apps Into Spies</a> (C. Warzel, <em>NYTimes. </em>Sept. 24, 2019<em>)</em><br><a href="https://themarkup.org/ask-the-markup/2022/02/24/who-is-policing-the-location-data-industry#2022-app-store-illustrated-explainer_numbered-list">Who Is Policing the Location Data Industry?</a> (A. Ng &amp; J. Keegan,,<em>The Markup. </em>Feb. 24, 2022)</p>
<h2>Control Your Online Presence</h2>
<h3>Social Media</h3>
<p>Bulk delete old tweets with the tool <a href="https://semiphemeral.com/">Semiphemeral</a>. You can also plan to delete them on an automatic schedule . See <a href="https://micahflee.com/2020/09/semiphemeral-automate-deleting-your-old-tweets-likes-and-direct-messages/">Instructions here</a>. Many customization options. You can also save a spreadsheet of your old tweets for personal archiving, if you want.</p>
<p>Delete or hide old Facebook posts in bulk (<a href="https://www.pcmag.com/how-to/quickly-delete-old-facebook-posts">Instructions from <em>PCMag</em></a>, 2021)</p>
<p>On Twitter, consider proactive blocking. The <a href="https://www.blockpartyapp.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Block Party app</a> provides multiple tools and strategies. </p>
<p>If you have social media accounts that you use primarily for communicating with friends and family (rather than professionally), consider making them private.</p>
<p>What kinds of information and images do you fell comfortable sharing going forward?</p>
<p class="msg msg--success">Guide: <a href="http://prcurtis.com/docs/twitterguide2/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">A Guide to Twitter and Social Media Safety for Academics (And Everyone Else)</a> by historian Paula R. Curtis</p>
<h3>University Websites &amp; Personal Websites</h3>
<p>Do you want a photo on your department website? Do you want your campus address posted on university or personal websites?</p>
<p>If you maintain a personal website, use a contact form rather than publishing your personal email address.</p>
<p>If you have a personal website, be sure to keep security patches updated.</p>
<h3>Your Academic Work</h3>
<p>Be aware that when you are emailing with colleagues at state universities, those conversations made be made public via FOIA requests.</p>
<p>Consider adding a copyright statement to your syllabus that prohibits students' posting course materials publicly. <a href="https://theuniversityfaculty.cornell.edu/dean/academic-integrity/students-buying-and-selling-course-materials/">This Faculty Senate page offers suggested language</a>. If you find your work posted on third party sites, you can request removal. Cornell Library Copyright Services offers <a href="https://guides.library.cornell.edu/copyright/course-material">a guide for finding re-posted course material and requesting its removal. </a></p>
<h3>Early Warning System</h3>
<p><a href="https://support.google.com/websearch/answer/4815696?hl=en" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Set up a Google alert for your name</a>, so that you will have a heads-up if you become a target.</p>
<p>Proactively request colleagues and family not share your contact information or personal details with cold callers or e-mailers. Consider speaking with your departmental administrative staff, and with anyone who is connected with your name in your academic work, or who you find linked to you in data-broker records.</p>
<h2>Plan in Advance: <br>How To Respond in the Event of an Attack</h2>
<p>Is there a friend you would trust to screen your email for you, so that you don't have to read the messages in the moment? Talk to them in advance.</p>
<p>Who in your personal or professional networks could you tap to report social media abuse? Threatening posts have a better chance of being taken down if reported by someone other than the target.</p>
<p>Will you want to save abusive materials in order to have documentation later?</p>
<p>Consider starting a conversation with colleagues in your unit or department about the collective harm of targeted and network harassment. As a group, consider how you might respond collectively, or not, to cases of sustained and severe harassment.</p>
<p>Consider contacting <a href="https://health.cornell.edu/services/victim-advocacy">Cornell Health's Victim Advocacy Program</a> for mental health and other support.</p>
<h2>Collective Harms &amp; Collective Responses</h2>
<p>It's important to remember that, while the largest burden of targeted or networked harassment is borne by individuals, the goal of such harassment is to discredit and delegitimize higher education, the academy, the research process, academic freedom, and academic institutions <em>collectively. </em></p>
<p>Therefore, the problem can never be solved by individual responses alone. Here are some resources to consider if you are planning collective defenses with your department, professional organization, or other group. </p>
<p>The American Association of University Professors (AAUP), informed by years of research and practice, <a href="https://www.aaup.org/news/targeted-online-harassment-faculty#.YU_bI6ApDfY">recommends </a>clear and forceful condemnations of harassment and intimidation from institutions, boards, and faculties, individually and collectively.</p>
<p><a href="https://facultyfirstresponders.com/responding-as-an-administrator/">How Should Administrators Respond to a Campus Reform Story?</a> (I. Kamola, Faculty First Responders Project)</p>
<p>A Model <a href="https://news.syr.edu/blog/2021/09/13/message-from-chancellor-kent-syverud-and-dean-david-van-slyke/">Public Message in Support of Targeted Faculty Member </a>(Syracuse University, Sept. 2021)</p>
<p><a href="https://www.aaup.org/sites/default/files/Cherniavsky-.pdf">Against the Common Sense: Academic Freedom as a Collective Right </a>(E. Cherinavsky. <em>Journal of Academic Freedom. </em>2021.)</p>
<h2>Understanding Harassment</h2>
<h6>First-person Accounts by Targeted Academics</h6>
<p><a data-cke-saved-href="https://www.uproot.space/features/confronting-anti-asian-racism" href="https://www.uproot.space/features/confronting-anti-asian-racism">Confronting Anti-Asian Racism: A Statement on (In)visibility and Online Targeted Harassment</a>, R. Esmail (2021), <em>Up//root. </em></p>
<p><a data-cke-saved-href="https://doi.org/10.1177/0891243218766831" href="https://doi.org/10.1177/0891243218766831">"Are You Willing to Die For This Work?" Public Targeted Online Harassment in Higher Education: SWS [Sociologists for Women in Society] Presidential Address</a>, A. L. Ferber (2018), <em>Gender &amp; Society </em>32(3)<em>.</em></p>
<h6>US-based Far-right </h6>
<p><a data-cke-saved-href="https://www.aaup.org/article/data-snapshot-whom-does-campus-reform-target-and-what-are-effects#.Yji_gJrMLFw" href="https://www.aaup.org/article/data-snapshot-whom-does-campus-reform-target-and-what-are-effects#.Yji_gJrMLFw">Data Snapshot: Whom Does Campus Reform Target and What Are the Effects?</a> H. Tiede, et.al., <em>American Association of University Professors Reports &amp; Publications.</em> Spring 2021</p>
<p><a data-cke-saved-href="https://www-tandfonline-com.proxy.library.cornell.edu/doi/full/10.1080/07393148.2021.1996837" href="https://www-tandfonline-com.proxy.library.cornell.edu/doi/full/10.1080/07393148.2021.1996837">Sensationalized Surveillance: Campus Reform and the Targeted Harassment of Faculty</a> S. McCarthy &amp; I. Kamola<em>, New Political Science.</em> Nov. 2021</p>
<p><a data-cke-saved-href="https://theintercept.com/2021/04/10/campus-reform-koch-young-americans-for-freedom-leadership-institute/" href="https://theintercept.com/2021/04/10/campus-reform-koch-young-americans-for-freedom-leadership-institute/">A Billionaire-Funded Website with Ties to the Far-Right Is Trying to "Cancel" University Professors</a> A. Speri, <em>The Intercept. </em>April 2021</p>
<p class="msg msg--success">Guide: <a href="https://facultyfirstresponders.com/">Faculty First Responders: Understand Right Wing Attacks on Faculty</a>, from political scientist Isaac Karmola</p>
<h6>Science-denialism</h6>
<p><a href="https://www.science.org/content/article/overwhelmed-hate-covid-19-scientists-face-avalanche-abuse-survey-shows">In the Line of Fire </a> C. O'Grady, <em>Science</em>, March 2022<br>On networked harassment of scientists, particularly those working on COVID-19 research.</p>
<h6>Foreign Affairs</h6>
<p><a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2021/10/03/india-us-universities-hindutva/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"></a><a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2021/10/03/india-us-universities-hindutva/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Under Fire from Hindu Nationalist Groups, U.S.-based Scholars of South Asia Worry About Academic Freedom</a> N. Masih, <em>The </em><em>Washington Post,</em> Oct. 3, 2021</p>
<p><a href="https://www.hrw.org/report/2021/06/30/they-dont-understand-fear-we-have/how-chinas-long-reach-repression-undermines" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">"They Don't Understand the Fear We Have": How China's Long Reach of Repression Undermines Academic Freedom at Australia's Universities</a> <em>Human Rights Watch, </em>June 30, 2021</p>
<p class="msg msg--success">Guide: <a href="https://www.hindutvaharassmentfieldmanual.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Hindutva Harassment Field Manual</a>, from the South Asia Scholar Activist Collective</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
